Register of the Japan, Koshikan (Korea) records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Copies of European-language telegrams to and from the Home Office, (Meiji 36, 37-nen obun dempo ofuku hikae), 1903 - 1904; 81 frames.
  Box/Folder 4: 189.
  Copies of English-language telegrams to and from Japanese Foreign Minister Komura and Japanese ministers in Germany, Great Britain, China, France, Russia, and other countries (transmitted to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke). Nov. 1, 1903 - Jan. 21, 1904.
- Documents relating to the use of the railroads by the [Japanese] Army, (Meiji 37, 38-nen gunyo tetsudo--2-4 gatsu), 1904 - 1905 (Feb. - Apr.); 94 frames. (Reel 6)
  Box/Folder 4: 192.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Japanese Foreign Minister Komura relating to use of Seoul-Pusan and Seoul-Shin'iju railroads by the Japanese Army. Documents relating to the construction of railroads and telegraph lines in northwestern Korea. Feb. 25 - Nov. 20, 1904.
  Missing frames: 56-69. Illegible fr.: 32, 33. 70-107 are renumbered 57-94. 32b, 33, 82 (69a) in English; 38 in Korean.
- Documents relating to the Treaty of Protection, (Meiji 38-nen hogo kyoyaku), 1905; 346 frames. (Reel 9)
  Box/Folder 4: 194.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Japanese Foreign Minister Katsura relating to Korean problems. Diplomatic correspondence between the Japanese Legation in Korea and the Korean Foreign Office concerning the domestic politics and foreign relations of Korea. Documents relating to the activities of the Ilchin'hoe party in favor of Japanese annexation of Korea; diplomatic negotiations of Prince Ito with the Korean government; texts of the Treaty of Protection between Japan and Korea; and the establishment of the Japanese Residency-General in Seoul. Sept. 15 - Dec. 6, 1905.
  Illegible frames: 6, 27, 28, 306. Generally difficult to read. 19 is followed by 19-1, -2, -3. 27, 28, 42b, 83-85, 88b, 89, 108, 109a, 222, 223, 296-298, 340 in Korean; 19-1 to 22a, 41b, 42a, 117, 118a, 119-122a, 130-133a, 151a, 152, 153a, 200a, 201a, 226a, 229a, 234a, 251a, 308, 309a, 311, 312a, 326, 332a in English; 327 in French.
- Instructions concerning Hasegawa, Maruyama, and Stevens; documents relating to the general [Japanese] plan for the installation of facilities in Korea; and the contract for the extension of the period of employment of Kato Masuo (Meiji 37, 38-nen Hasegawa, Maruyama, Suchibunsu ni taisuru kunrei oyobi taikan shisetsu koryo narabini Kato Masuo keiyaku enhei), 69 frames. (Reel 18)
  Box/Folder 5: 196.
  Correspondence to and from Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Japanese Foreign Minister Komura relating to the appointment of General Hasegawa Yoshimichi as the Commander of the Japanese armed forces in Korea. Documents relating to the arrival of an American, Durham White Stevens, and other advisers to the Korean Foreign Office. General Japanese plan for the construction of harbors, railroads, telegraph lines, and other facilities for military purposes in Korea. Texts of contracts relating to the employment of Stevens and Kato Masuo. Oct. 6, 1904 - Aug. 21, 1905.
  4, 5, 66-69 in Korean; 14-16a, 20-22a in English.
- Miscellany, (Meiji 38-nen zatsu), 1905; 73 frames. (Reel 9)
  Box/Folder 5: 206.
  Miscellaneous file of administrative reports from the Japanese Postmaster General and other Japanese officials in Korea to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke. Documents relating to the popular uprising in Korea in 1905.
  7-13 contain tables. 18b contains a map.
- Documents relating to whaling, (Meiji 32-37-nen hogei), 1899 - 1904; 30 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 212.
  Chinese and English texts of an agreement between Korea and Russia dealing with whaling off the northeastern coast of Korea. Mar. 29, 1900.
  Nearly all frames are illegible. 1-14 in English.
- Telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Home Office, --Part IV (Meiji 38-nen honsho oden-shi), 1905; 168 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 216.
  Telegrams sent by Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Hagiwara and Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke to Japanese Foreign Minister Komura relating to the popular uprising in northeast Korea; and Korean foreign relations. Texts of the Japanese-Korean treaty signed by Minister Hayashi and Korean Foreign Minister Pak Che-sun transferring the administration of Korea's foreign affairs to the Japanese Foreign Ministry. Correspondence of Hayashi with Japanese Foreign Minister Katsura relating to the reactions of Korean political leaders to the Hayashi-Pak treaty. Nov. 2, 1905 - Jan. 18, 1906.
  Missing frame: 66. Illegible fr.: 95, 100, 106, 125, 156b.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Japanese Consulate in Mokp'o and its Kunsan Branch, (Meiji 38-nen Moppo, Gunzan orai), 1905; 13 frames. (Reel 19)
  Box/Folder 5: 219.
  Reports of Japanese Consul Wakamatsu Usaburo in Mokp'o and the Head of the Kunsan Branch of the Mokp'o Consulate Yokota Saburo submitted to the Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke relating to the activities of pro-Japanese Ilchin'hoe party. Mar. 22 - Nov. 25, 1905.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Japanese Consulate in Inchon, --Part I (Meiji 38-nen Jinsen orai-1), 1905; 10 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 224.
  The report of Japanese Consul in Inchon Kato Motoshiro to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke relating to the dispatch of Russian secret envoy to Korea. Summary of a speech by President Theodore Roosevelt on the Russo-Japanese War. Jan. 7 - June 12, 1905.
  Missing frame: 5. Two frames are numbered 6.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Japanese Consulates in Seoul and Inchon, --Part I (Meiji 38-nen Keijo, Jinsen orai-1), 1905; 41 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 226.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Japanese Consul in Seoul Mimashi Kumekichi and Japanese Consul in Inchon Kato Motoshiro relating to the activities of the members of the Ilchin'hoe party. Jan. 1-26, 1905.
  31 is followed by 31-1.
- Correspondence of the Japanese Legation in Korea with the Korean Imperial Court, --Part II (Meiji 38-nen kyuchu ofuku-2), 1905; 7 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 236.
  Correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Korean Minister of Rites and Ceremonies Min Chong-muk relating to Yi Yong-ik, including the letter of Japanese Chargé d'Affaires Hagiwara to Yi Yong-ik dated Oct. 16, 1905.
  1, 2, 5, 7a in Korean.
- Telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea to and from the Japanese consulates in Pusan and Masan, (Meiji 38-nen Fuzan Masan Orai-den), 1905; 5 frames. (Reel 10)
  Box/Folder 5: 240.
  Telegraphic correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and the Japanese Consul in Pusan relating to the Russian dispatch of a secret mission to the Korean Imperial Court. A telegram from the Headquarters of the Japanese Army in Korea relating to the arrival of a Russian secret envoy to Korea. Apr. 6 and Nov. 9, 1905.
- Correspondence between the Japanese Army Commander and the Chief of Japanese Gendarmerie in Korea, -- Part I (Meiji 38-nen gunken orai-1), 1905; 18 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 241.
  Correspondence transmitted to Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke by the Commander of the Japanese Army in Korea relating to the riots against the Ilchin'hoe party in the Ch0nju area; and military cooperation between the Russians and Koreans in North Hamgy[UNK]ong Province directed against the Japanese. Jan. 8 - July 7, 1905.
- Documents relating to the transfer of official business from the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Japanese Residency-General, (Meiji 38-nen juichigatsu Koshikan tai Tokanfu jimu yoko hikitsugi), Nov. 1905; 28 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 243
- Telegrams of the Japanese Legation in Korea, (Meiji 38, 39-nen oden ji juichigatsu itaru sangatsu), Nov. 1905 - Mar. 1906; 12 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 244.
  Telegrams sent by Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke to Japanese Foreign Minister Kato Takaaki relating to the withdrawal of foreign consulates from Korea. Jan. 9 - Feb. 9, 1906.
- Copies of telegrams sent in (Meiji 39-nen denso hikaetsuzuri sangatsu, shigatsu), Mar. and Apr. 1906; 22 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 246.
  Telegrams sent by Japanese Foreign Minister Saionji to Resident-General Ito relating to diplomatic communications between Russia and Great Britain concerning the withdrawal of foreign consulates from Korea and the question of Korean independence. Mar. 15 - Apr. 20, 1906.
  Two different frames numbered 16.
- Telegrams received by the Japanese Legation in Korea (Meiji 39-nen denju juichigatsu junigatsu), Nov. - Dec. 1906; 26 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 248.
  Telegrams relating to the arrest of Min Chong-sik; aid to Korean students sent to Japan by the Ilchin'hoe party; and the dispatch of a Special Korean Envoy to Japan. Nov. 6 - Dec. 31, 1906.
- Telegrams sent, (Meiji 39-nen oden), 1906; 71 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 249.
  Telegraphic correspondence of Director-General of the Residency-General Tsuruhara Sadakichi with Japanese Vice-Minister of Foreign Affairs Chinda Sutemi, and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and Resident-General Ito relating to the domestic politics and foreign relations of Korea. Documents relating to the policy of the Residency-General regarding foreign-operated mines and other foreign-owned facilities in Korea. Apr. 22 - Nov. 19, 1906.
  19 is followed by 19-1.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 39-nen raiden ji shigatsu itaru rokugatsu), Apr. - June, 1906; 119 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 250.
  Telegraphic correspondence from Japanese Vice-Minister of Foreign Affairs Chinda to Resident-General Ito relating to Russian diplomatic notes regarding Korea sent to Germany, France, Austria, Italy, and the United States. Documents relating to popular uprising in central Korea. Correspondence between Resident-General Ito and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to Russo-Japanese relations and Russian diplomats in Korea. Apr. 10 - Nov. 19, 1906.
  Missing frames: 87, 88. Two different frames numbered 67. 66b-68, 74b-78, 83-85, 95b-98, 110b-112 in English.
- History of the Thirteen Provinces, Chientao and the course of the Tumen River, (Meiji 39-nen Jusando oyobi Kanto Tomanko ichi enkaku), 1906; 119 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 251.
  History of the thirteen provinces of Korea and territorial problems involving the region of Kando (Chientao) and the Tumen River. 1906.
- Copies of telegrams received, (Meiji 39-nen setsuju dempo hikae), 1906; 33 frames. (Reel 19)
  Box/Folder 5: 252.
  Copies of telegrams received by the Residency-General from Japanese Minister in Korea Hayashi Gonsuke and Japanese Police Inspector-General Maruyama Shigetoshi relating to changes in the Korean cabinet; anti-Japanese uprisings in various areas; the activities of Iby0ng ("Righteous Army"); and the arrival of the Saionji Mission to Korea. May 4 - June 13, 1906.
  Each frame is also marked 729.
- Reports of the Residency-General, (Meiji 39-nen Tokanfu hokoku), 1906; 91 frames. (Reel 10)
  Box/Folder 5: 253.
  Reports submitted by the Director-General of the Residency-General to Resident-General Ito concerning administrative, diplomatic, and other affairs in Korea under his jurisdiction. Documents relating to secret Russo-Korean negotiations; and the affairs involving Han Kyu-s0l, Yi Kun t'aek, Yi Yong-ik, Min Y0ng-don, and Yi Ki-gy0n. Dec. 1 - 28, 1906.
  Illegible frames: 78b, 79a. Each frame is also numbered 745. 71a contains a map. 37-39, 43-51, 60-68 in English; 40-42, 52-59 in French.
- Documents of the Japanese Legation and consulates in Korea, (Meiji 39-nen koryojikan kankei), 1906; 8 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 254.
  Documents relating to the transfer of official business from the Japanese Legation in Korea to the Japanese Residency-General. July 17, 1906 - Jan. 7, 1907.
  7b, 8a in Korean.
- Records of the Departments of Agriculture, Industry, and Commerce, (Meiji 39-nen Nokoshomubu jimu seiseki), 1906; 180 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 255.
  Administrative reports of the departments of Agriculture, Commerce, and Industry of the Residency-General.
  Each frame is also numbered 749.
- Documents relating to the Chientao problem, (Meiji 40-nen Kanto mondai ni kansuru shorui), 1907; 294 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 256.
  Documents dealing with Korean-Chinese relations and civil administration in Kando (Chientao) area; and the problem of the Korean-Chinese boundary. Documents relating to civil disturbances in northeast Korea. Nov. 1 - Dec. 31, 1907.
  Missing frame: 239. Each frame is also numbered 770. 139, 140a, 141b, 142a in Korean.
- File of telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju tsuzurikomi), 1907; 55 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 257.
  Telegrams sent by Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and others to Resident-General Ito relating to the trial of foreigners under Korean laws; and the visit of the Korean Crown Prince to Japan. Oct. 3 - Nov. 30, 1907.
  Illegible frames: 29, 35b. Each frame is also numbered 797. 3b-5 in English.
- Documents relating to the Chientao problem, (Meiji 39, 40-nen Kanto mondai ni kansuru shorui), 1906 - 1907; 475 frames. (Reel 11)
  Box/Folder 5: 259.
  Correspondence between Resident-General Ito and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to Kando [Chientao]; and Sino-Japanese negotiations dealing with this problem. Dec. 11, 1906 - Oct. 31, 1907.
  Missing frames: 262, 448. Illegible fr.: 154, 155, 233. Each frame is also numbered 769. 1-19 contain a Table of Contents; 89, 90 contain tables; 103b contains a map. 22, 23a, 28a-50 in Korean.
- Reports of the Bureau of Railroad Administration [of the Residency-General], (Meiji 40-nen Tetsudo Kanrikyoku hokoku), 1907; 6 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 260.
  Each frame is also numbered 786.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju), 1907; 73 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 261.
  Telegraphic correspondence of Resident-General Ito with Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and others relating to the question of amnesty for Korean political prisoners. Documents relating to Pak Y0ng-hyo in exile; Ernest T. Bethell, the editor of the English-language Korea Daily News in Seoul; and American-operated mines in Korea. Jan. 9 - June 25, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 794. Two different frames each numbered 30 through 39. 14b, 15, 26b-29 in English.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju), 1907; 122 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 262.
  Telegrams of Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu to Resident-General Ito relating to the Russo-Japanese secret treaty and the Franco-Japanese convention. Documents relating to Russo-Japanese relations in Korea and Manchuria. Correspondence between Japanese Minister to Russia Motono Ichiro and Hayashi concerning the problem of Mongolia in Russo-Japanese negotiations.
  Each frame is also numbered 795. 5-9, 14b, 15, 19b-21, 26b, 27a, 31b, 47b, 48, 66, 71-74, 75-77, 79-83, 85b-87, 116b-118 in English.
- General file of telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju sokatsu), 1907; 99 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 263.
  Telegraphic correspondence between Deputy Resident-General Sone Arasuke and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to Sino-Japanese relations concerning Kando (Chientao) and its Korean population, and Yuan Shih-k'ai's policy toward Chientao. Dec. 6-28, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 799. 1 to 86 is followed by 1 to 13. 61 slightly damaged.
- Reports of Special Official Uchida, (Meiji 40-nen Uchida shokutaku hokoku), 1907; 47 frames. (Reel 19)
  Box/Folder 5: 264.
  Reports submitted to the Resident-General Ito by Uchida Ryohei on the activities of Iby0ng ("Righteous Army"); the organization of Chawidan ("Self DefenseLeague"); and conditions in the vicinity of Seoul. Nov. 26-30, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 789. 11-32 contain tables.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju), 1907; 134 frames. (Reel 11)
  Box/Folder 5: 265.
  Telegrams sent to Resident-General Ito during his stay in Tokyo by Deputy Resident-General Hasegawa Toshimichi and others relating to the activities of Iby0ng ("Righteous Army"); and popular uprisings on the Kanghwado Island and in Kang'won and Ch'ungch'0ng provinces. Documents relating to the trial of Pak Y0ng-hyo; and the abdication of Emperor Kojong, and the coronation of the Emperor Sungjong. Aug. 11 - Sept. 27, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 796.
- File of telegrams sent, (Meiji 40-nen oden tsuzurikomi), 1907; 12 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 266.
  Telegrams sent by Resident-General Ito and others to Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to the trial of Ernest T. Bethell. Oct. 14-16, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 803. 4-6 in English.
- Copies of telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen raiden hikae), 1907; 241 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 267.
  Telegrams received by Resident-General Ito relating to the activities of Korean political refugees abroad; Shin ng-hi and Yi Kyu-wan, Emperor Kojong's secret emissaries to the Hague Peace Conference; and the British, French, and American attitudes toward this action. Documents relating to Ilchin'hoe party and political conditions in Korea. July 1 - Sept. 24, 1907.
  Missing frames: 50, 65. Each frame is also numbered 798. 10b, 11, 18b-21, 23b-31, 33b-35, 42b-44, 62-71, 106-111, 113-117, 120-141, 143-148, 152-157 in English.
- Telegrams sent, (Meiji 40-nen denso), 1907; 57 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 268.
  Telegrams exchanged between Resident-General Ito and Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu relating to the trial of Ernest T. Bethell; Russian interests in Iju and Yong'amp'o areas; the resignation of Korean Foreign Minister Pak Che-sun and his succession by Yi Wan-yong; and the return of Pak Y0ng-hyo to Korea. Jan. 29 - June 28, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 801. 51-53 in English.
- Copies of telegrams received [by Resident-General Ito], during official tour, (Meiji 39, 40-nen shutchochu setsuju denshin hikae), 1906 - 1907; 129 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 269.
  Telegrams from Director-General of the Residency-General Tsuruhara and others to Resident-General Ito during his stay in Tokyo relating to the changes in Korean cabinet; Korean Special Envoy to Japan Yi Chi-yong, popular uprising in the Ky0ngsang provinces; the visit of Austrian Prince Leopold to the Korean court; the conflict between Pak Che-sun and Yi Chong-k0n; Pak Y0ng-hyo; Ernest T. Bethell; and the properties owned by the British, French, and Italian firms in Korea. Nov. 25, 1906 - Mar. 15, 1907.
  Illegible frame: 117. Each frame is also numbered 800.
- Telegrams sent, (Meiji 40-nen oden), 1907; 178 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 270.
  Confidential documents relating to the Korean secret mission to the Hague Peace Conference; the abdication of Emperor Kojong and the coronation of Emperor Sunjong; the abolition of the Korean Army; the movement of Italian warships in Korean waters; editor Ernest T. Bethell and the Korea Daily News; and the journey of Korean Crown Prince Yi n to Japan July 3 - Dec. 28, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 802. 82a in English.
- File of telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju tsuzurikomi), 1907; 49 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 272.
  Telegrams sent by Resident-General Ito and others to Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and others relating to anti-Japanese insurrections; the Bethell affair; and the pardoning of Yi P0m-nae and six other Koreans who were arrested and tried for assassination of Queen Min. Aug. 12 - Sept. 28, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 804.
- File of telegrams received, (Meiji 40-nen denju tsuzurikomi), 1907; 40 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 273.
  Telegrams received by Resident-General Ito from Japanese Foreign Minister Hayashi Tadasu and Prime Minister Saionji relating to the adviser to the Japanese Foreign Ministry H. W. Denison and the sending of Yi Chi-yong and others with the Korean Crown Prince Yi n to Japan. Apr. 9 - Dec. 9, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 805. 9-12 in English.
- File of documents, (Meiji 40-nen monjo tsuzurikomi), 1907; 136 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 274.
  Documents relating to the coronation of the Emperor Sunjong; popular uprisings in Korea; and Sino-Japanese negotiation regarding the Korean-Manchurian boundary. Aug. 7 - Sept. 11, 1907.
  Illegible frame: 34. Each frame is also numbered 807; 78 renumbered 68. 51b-56 contain tables. 69-74 in Korean; 93 in English.
- Documents relating to the recognition of Korean laws and regulations, (Meiji 40-nen Kankoku hoki shonin shorui), 1907; 46 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 277.
  Documents relating to the Korean taxation system. Portions of the Korean Official Gazette. May 11, 1906 - Sept. 22, 1907.
  Each frame is also numbered 810. 24-37, 39-42, 46 contain tables. 1, 12b-17a in Korean.
- Miscellaneous file, (Meiji 41-nen zattetsu), 1907-1908; 36 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 279.
  Documents relating to Ernest T. Bethell; and the return of Pak Y0ng-hyo to Korea. Communications between the Chief of the Bureau of Trade of the Residency-General Hagiwara Shuichi, and Deputy Resident-General Sone relating to the purchase of American railroad and other interests in Korea. July 14 - Oct. 31, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 856. 17b in Korean.
- Miscellaneous file, (Meiji 40-nen, 41-nen zattetsu), 1907-1908; 29 frames.
  Box/Folder 5: 280.
  Miscellaneous documents and telegrams relating to the insurrection in North Hamgy0ng Province; the appointment of Yi Hak-sang as a guardian to Crown Prince Yi n during his studies in Tokyo. Dec. 27, 1907 - June 6, 1908.
  Each frame is also numbered 855.
- Copies of Japanese-language telegrams, --supplement (Meiji 27-nen wabun dempo ofuku hikae tsuika), 1894; 90 frames. (Reel 12)
  Box/Folder 5: 281.
  Telegraphic correspondence between Japanese Minister in Korea Otori and Japanese consuls in Korea; and between Japanese Minister in Korea Inoue Kaoru and Japanese military and diplomatic officials in Korea. July 4 - Dec. 8, 1894.
  Each frame is also marked 213 tsuika.
- Reports of the Telegraph Bureau, (Meiji 40-nen Tsushin Kanrikyoku hokoku). 243 frames. Reel XII, 1907
  Box/Folder 5: 282.
  Reports of the Chief of the Telegraph Bureau of the Residency-General Ikeda Jusaburo to Resident-General Ito. File of telegram drafts handled by the Bureau. Apr. 15 - July 23, 1907.
  Missing frame: 121. Illegible fr.: 43, 226-231. Each frame is also numbered 782; two different frames each numbered 130, 145 through 149. 6, 23-38, 40-46, 48, 49, 51, 70a, 71, 72, 81-83, 90, 91, 93, 94, 95b-102, 112b-116, 127-131, 145b-147, 149-156, 185, 189, 191-213, 215, 225a-230, 233-237 in English.
- Miscellaneous file, (Meiji 38, 41-nen zassan), 1905 and 1908; 203 frames. (Reel 19)
  Box/Folder 5: 283.
  Miscellaneous documents of the Residency-General relating to the American attitude toward Japanese rule in Korea; cancellation of a proposed Japanese loan of 1,500,000 yen to Korea; the policies of the Residency-General in Korea; Korean political refugees abroad; Franco-Korean diplomatic relations; the visit of a special Korean envoy to Japan; Pak Y0ng-hyo; local uprisings in North Ch'ungch'0ng Province; the establishment of Toyo Takushoku Kaisha (Oriental Development Company); Korean police; and the organization and activities of Chawidan ("Self Defense League") against Iby0ng ("Righteous Army") in various provinces. Reports of special official of the Residency-General Uchida Ryohei on the political and military activities of the Iby0ng against the Ilchin'hoe party and its members. Dec. 18, 1905 - Feb. 13, 1908.
  Missing frames: 42, 175. Each frame is also numbered 854. 40, 41 on one frame. 152, 153a contain maps. 2, 61b in English; 32-35a in French.
- Telegrams received, (Meiji 41-nen denju ji ichigatsu itaru shigatsu), Jan. - Apr. 1908; 50 frames. (Reel 12)
  Box/Folder 5: 284.